[vpnXpert](https://vpnxpert.com/) › Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy
==============

At **vpnXpert**, we aim to provide you with the latest tech news and to stress the importance of privacy. Thus, in our Privacy Policy you can find out how we deal with personal data processing.

By visiting and interacting with our website, you are deemed to have accepted to be bound by our Privacy Policy.

If you have any questions or comments regarding this Policy, please reach out to us via our Contact form.

Contact
-------

If you use our Contact, we will process the name and email address you have provided. We would process these pieces of data based on our legitimate interest to get in touch with you and/or based on some other lawful grounds, when applicable. When you make a comment on our stories we process your IP address as well. We do that based on our legitimate interest to make sure that a comment comes from a legitimate visitor.

Cookies and related technologies
--------------------------------

Cookies, pixels and other similar technologies are usually small text or image files that are placed on your device when visiting our website. The use of such technologies is standard on the Internet. You can choose whether to accept or block cookies through your browser settings. You can decide to delete cookies as well. All major browsers allow users to choose their cookie settings.  
We mostly use and manage the following types of third-party cookies:

* cookies that help us make our website usable by enabling basic functions like page navigation and access to secure areas of the website. The website cannot function properly without these cookies; for example, \_\_cfduid cookie, which expires after 29 days;
* cookies used for statistical purposes. These cookies help us understand how visitors interact with the websites; for instance, csi/batch (lasts for a session), \_gat and \_gid (last 1 day), ab (lasts up to 1 year), \_ga and personalization\_id (last up to 2 years);
* marketing cookies; the intention of using these cookies is to display information that is relevant and engaging for the individual user; for example, ads/ga-audiences, dpixel, g/collect, i/adsct, pcs/activeview, pixel/#, trk, w/1.0/sd, YSC, yt-remote-cast-installed, yt-remote-fast-check-period, yt-remote-session-app and yt-remote-session-name (last for a session), na\_sr, na\_sc\_e, na\_rn (last for up to 29 days), CMPRO, CMPS, KADUSERCOOKIE (last up to 3 months), VISITOR\_INFO1\_LIVE, uid, (lasts for up to 179 days), CMID, id, IDE, mdata, ov, uuid (last for up to 1 year), cref, mc, na\_id, na\_tc, ouid (last up to 13 months), \_ga\_KT8DKCHF41 (lasts up to 2 years), Yt-remote-device-id, yt-remote-connected-devices, google\_pem\_mod, google\_experiment\_mod#, google\_ama\_config, google\_adsense\_settings (persistent cookies).

Our website may collect access logs (e.g., IP address, browser used, etc.) as well. We use this data to prevent cyber attacks, based on our legitimate interests of information security. At the moment our website does not respond to Do-not-track signals because no such standard has been adopted yet.

We might process your personal data with an intent to offer the best quality of vpnXpert content, i.e., by adjusting our website to your device as well as offering the content fit to you and similar.

Data retention period
---------------------

We may store the data for as long as it would be reasonably necessary to make sure we would be able to comply with legal requirements (for example, requirements of record keeping) and/or to establish a legal claim or defend ourselves from one.

Data transfers and safeguards
-----------------------------

We use some third-party service providers (such as email, website analytics and other information and communication technology services) for the processing of your personal data. They can access the data only as much as is needed for the provision of the services. We also ensure that transfers of such data to a third country or an international organization are subject to appropriate safeguards.  
We may disclose your personal data to a law enforcement agency, government authority or other organisation if we are required to do so to meet our legal obligations, or otherwise to protect our rights or the rights of anyone else.  
We use social media (Facebook, Twitter, etc.) sharing functions. Such social media widgets may collect certain information (e.g., your IP address or the type of device you are using) and transmit it to the respective social media organizations. For more information on how these organisations use personal data, please read their privacy policies. Here, we act on the basis of our legitimate interests to share our knowledge and be visible on the market.

Your data protection and privacy rights
---------------------------------------

You have certain data protection and privacy rights.

You have the right to know what kind of your personal data we process, ask us to update, delete or stop processing information we hold about you. However, please note that there could be circumstances in which complete erasure of your information or ceasing to process your information would not be possible due to operational, legal and business reasons. Where you have provided us with consent to use your personal data, you can withdraw this at any time. You may also have the right to ask us to send you the data we hold about you.

If you wish to make a request with regards to your data protection rights, please get in touch with us via our Contact form. You may have a right to contact your local data protection authority as well. However, we would ask you to reach out to us first, since we believe that together we could solve any issues.

Keeping your data safe
----------------------

We take information security seriously and put a great effort to ensure the information we hold on you remains safe. We limit who has access to your information and ensure that those who do are bound by contracts to keep your information availability restricted and safe.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure. And even though we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted through any online means; therefore, any transmission remains at your own risk.

External links
--------------

Our website may contain links to and from other websites. These websites have their own privacy notices and/or terms of service. We do not accept any responsibility or

liability for these other websites. Please make sure to check the above mentioned documents before submitting any personal data to these websites.

Individuals under age of 14
---------------------------

We do not intentionally, or knowingly, process personal information from individuals under the age of 14. We will make every effort to delete any details of such individuals where we are informed that these details have been collected.

Other terms
-----------

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time. This may be in relation to changes in the law, best practice or changes in our services. Any changes will become effective when we post the revised Privacy Policy; thus, you should check here regularly.

### Contact Us

We are happy to answer questions about our platform or any commerce-related matter. Please feel free to reach out.

Our team consists of experienced experts who know all the latest trends in VPN, privacy, and cybersecurity.

Our goal is to show that anyone can use a VPN without any restrictions. And everyone has the right to a private Internet.

©vpnxpert.com 2022

© 2022 – vpnXpert.com
